<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <docs>https://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <title>The Tvdb on Victor Toso</title>
    <link>http://victortoso.com/tags/the-tvdb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Tvdb on Victor Toso</description>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo 0.55.0-DEV</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 23:34:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
      <atom:link href="http://victortoso.com/tags/the-tvdb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Report #4 and #5</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1406/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 23:34:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1406/</guid>
        <description>Hey :) I usually write my posts in the weekend when I do have more time to think about what I&amp;rsquo;ve done and what It is interesting to share. Sadly, two weekends ago I was ill due something I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten and now I&amp;rsquo;ll try to summarize two weeks in one post!
The TVDB Is now upstream. Yay!
The main care after implementing the cache with Gom was handling multiple requests of the same TV Show in a short period of time (concurrency).</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Hey :) I usually write my posts in the weekend when I do have more time to think about what I&amp;rsquo;ve done and what It is interesting to share. Sadly, two weekends ago I was ill due something I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten and now I&amp;rsquo;ll try to summarize two weeks in one post!
The TVDB Is now upstream. Yay!
The main care after implementing the cache with Gom was handling multiple requests of the same TV Show in a short period of time (concurrency).
For instance, you are browsing some TV Show using some application that uses Grilo to requests metadata. It may occur several requests of the same tv show like, episode 01, episode 02, etc.
We are handling this by fetching the TVDB only once to gather all existing data and then resolve the later requests with the cache.
Quite nice, lots of fun implementing it.
The Integration with the UI I have realized I&amp;rsquo;m really bad at building UIs and I&amp;rsquo;m also recognizing how much effort it is necessary to make a good UI (a lot).
For that, I would like to thank the folks from Glade with the awesome and helpful software.
Well, at the moment I&amp;rsquo;m implementing a simple program that creates a Widget to show all interesting information we will be providing on GNOME Videos. You may check the application here.
The goal: Current status Life World cup is going on, traffic jam everywhere but people are in quite good mood here in Brazil. I&amp;rsquo;m happier mostly because of my new great friend, Marvin.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC 2014 Report #2 - The TVDB - Tests and Libs</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1404/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 01:58:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1404/</guid>
        <description>Keep moving! One of the great features of the TVDB is all the image gallery that they have and provide. To get as much interesting data as possible using Grilo we need to extend our source and a great way to do it is through creating custom metadata-keys.
With these newly created metadata-keys the TVDB source can now provide an url to the most voted Fanart, Poster and Banner of the tv show.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Keep moving! One of the great features of the TVDB is all the image gallery that they have and provide. To get as much interesting data as possible using Grilo we need to extend our source and a great way to do it is through creating custom metadata-keys.
With these newly created metadata-keys the TVDB source can now provide an url to the most voted Fanart, Poster and Banner of the tv show.
Tests I had included a few tests in the first week but it was just to show that the source was usable. The current version of the tests check if the source is finding the right data in a resolve operation.
Simple enough but helped a lot finding bugs already :)
Libs Well, I thought it would be nice to point a few libraries that I have never used before implementing this source:
 Libxml: Yes, never! I always choose JSON when available! :) The library has a nice documentation with samples but what really helped me was others sources in Grilo. I&amp;rsquo;ve also realized that I&amp;rsquo;m not big fan of camelCase. Libarchive: I&amp;rsquo;ve come to know about this library in Planet feed when Bastien posted about it. Currently it is also included in Lua-Factory with a function which provides &amp;lsquo;unzip&amp;rsquo; to lua-sources in Grilo. Quite awesome. Libgom: Awesome but not very easy. The examples and the blog posts are the best documentation. I&amp;rsquo;ve started with a simple DB and at this moment I&amp;rsquo;m envolving from there before applying it to the TVDB.  Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;m going to finish the coding of the TVDB source soon enough and then I&amp;rsquo;ll be starting the integration with Totem GNOME Videos. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to see all work combined.
Relax Beautiful GNOME-shaped soap. Smells so good!
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC 2014 Report #1 - The TVDB</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1403/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 23:34:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1403/</guid>
        <description>Start This is the first weekend since the beginning of GSoC coding period and it has been satisfactory. For those that have no clue on what I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on this summer, part of it is implementing TV Shows support in GNOME Videos!
In order to provide all information necessary to the interface, we will be using Grilo with the The TVDB source which is what I&amp;rsquo;m working on at the moment.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Start This is the first weekend since the beginning of GSoC coding period and it has been satisfactory. For those that have no clue on what I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on this summer, part of it is implementing TV Shows support in GNOME Videos!
In order to provide all information necessary to the interface, we will be using Grilo with the The TVDB source which is what I&amp;rsquo;m working on at the moment.
The TVDB The TVDB is an &amp;amp;quot;open database for television fans&amp;amp;quot; and it is just awesome. This database provides tons of information and images of series and episodes in several languages. It is a great source for Grilo and will fulfill completely our need.
I strongly recommend a little browsing in the image gallery which has banners, fan art, posters like House, Breaking Bad. They have animes too like Naruto or Evangelion.
Grilo Source: grl-thetvdb The first version is up on bugzilla not ready to upstream yet but it is functional. At this stage I&amp;rsquo;m not holding the data locally in any form. Every time the application request something to grl-thetvdb it will fetch the data from thetvdb.com which is poor design.
But thats all I&amp;rsquo;ve got for this first week!
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
