<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <docs>https://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <title>Victor Toso</title>
    <link>http://victortoso.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Victor Toso</description>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo 0.55.0-DEV</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 12:20:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
      <atom:link href="http://victortoso.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>New ways to remote desktops with GStreamer integration</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/talks/1701/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 12:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/talks/1701/</guid>
        <description>Once again at DevConf CZ but now to talk about SPICE and its integration with GStreamer. Together with my friend and colleague Pavel Grunt we give a brief explanation about how SPICE works and then we focus on the image display and video streaming part of SPICE protocol while trying to clarify why streaming is so important to remote desktops.
Video Slides</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Once again at DevConf CZ but now to talk about SPICE and its integration with GStreamer. Together with my friend and colleague Pavel Grunt we give a brief explanation about how SPICE works and then we focus on the image display and video streaming part of SPICE protocol while trying to clarify why streaming is so important to remote desktops.
Video Slides
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Playing with Desktop Integration</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1602/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 15:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1602/</guid>
        <description>Thanks to a bug found in Spice&amp;rsquo;s drag and drop implementation, I was able to improve the integration of our guest agent (spice-vdagent) with the Desktop Session on Linux and Windows. I enjoyed the process to solve those problems so I thought a blog post could be interesting as well.
The problem If you use Spice you might enjoy the feature of copying files from your client machine to the guest by simply using the drag and drop feature.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Thanks to a bug found in Spice&amp;rsquo;s drag and drop implementation, I was able to improve the integration of our guest agent (spice-vdagent) with the Desktop Session on Linux and Windows. I enjoyed the process to solve those problems so I thought a blog post could be interesting as well.
The problem If you use Spice you might enjoy the feature of copying files from your client machine to the guest by simply using the drag and drop feature. It works pretty well and under the hood we are sending this data to spice-vdagent which copies it to your Download or Desktop folder.
The problem is that you could transfer files with drag and drop while your guest session was Locked (rhbz#1323623); even worse, it was also possible to transfer files when your guest were on Login Screen, when no user was logged in (rhbz#1328761).
In order to fix both issues, we need to ask (someone) about the Session state, the following questions &amp;quot;Is the session Locked?&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Does this session belong to a user?&amp;quot;. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how we can do that.
Linux Guests In order to solve this in the best way possible, I did not want to make integration with specific Desktop Environment (DE) so, I started looking for a cross Desktop API.
My first try was around org.freedesktop.ScreenSaver interface which worked rather well. I had a few issues that I might be able to workaround but it did not seem right to request ScreenSaver the state of your user session.
So I looked at logind from systemd and there I could find a very promising &amp;lsquo;Lock&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Unlock&amp;rsquo; signals! I checked with gdbus monitor if this was being used in my session with:
# get your session path with: gdbus call --system --dest org.freedesktop.login1 \ --object-path /org/freedesktop/login1 \ --method org.freedesktop.login1.Manager.ListSessions # monitor it gdbus monitor --system --dest org.freedesktop.login1 \ --object-path /org/freedesktop/login1/session/_31 # Lock an then Unlock your session with GNOME and see: /org/freedesktop/login1/session/_31: org.freedesktop.login1.Session.Unlock()  So, the Unlock signal was emitted but not the Lock signal. I thought it could be a bug so a filed #764773 to discuss it. It was not a bug and tracking the Lock and Unlock signals was not the best approach.
After some discussion with halfline we agreed that extending logind would make things easier. Lennart pointed that having a LockedHint property with SetLockedHint method would be a nice thing to have.
This would make rather simple to programs like spice-vdagent to query the Locked state of the Session.
The proposal was accepted and works well. One less bug to solve.
Back to the bad transfer over Login screen, that happens because we have a spice-vdagent running for GDM so we can do things like resizing the display correctly and as soon as possible.
The solution was rather simple here, all you need to do is to check your session class. We are only interested in a session that belongs to &amp;quot;User&amp;quot; and sd_session_get_class() can give you that.
That&amp;rsquo;s it for Linux guests. I also patched our console-kit integration but I don&amp;rsquo;t plan to comment on it. Take a look in this commit to check for the session class and this one to check if we are in a Locked session.
Many many thanks to halfline for his time and help, it was really fun.
Windows I wasn&amp;rsquo;t excited on the windows part so I postpone for some time but in the end, It was surprisingly easy. We only have one bug here due the design difference between our agents: the transfer while Guest is in Locked screen.
On Windows you can subscribe for session notifications and the event WTSRegisterSessionNotification has WTS_SESSION_LOCK and WTS_SESSION_UNLOCK types. Very handy. Minimum requirements say &amp;lsquo;Windows Vista&amp;rsquo; but it works on &amp;lsquo;Windows XP&amp;rsquo; as well. Super!
As we were already listening to sessions notifications, I only had to handle the lock/unlock events type (here).
Conclusion I&amp;rsquo;m naive. I thought I would have much more work with Desktop integration on Windows then on Linux! I&amp;rsquo;ll be more careful with my thoughts next time :)
Bugs bugs bugs.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Grilo updates!</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1601/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1601/</guid>
        <description>Nothing like talking about Grilo to keep the blog going and to be honest I have some interesting things to talk about.
Grilo 0.3 The major release happened almost 6 months ago and it has brought some API/ABI changes being my favourite the merge of all Grilo media types into GrlMedia (#755551); This introduces support from Grilo to different types of media!
Well, to be pedantic, it was always possible to have different media types in Grilo on GrlMedia but it is more clear to applications by merging GrlMedia{Audio,Video,Image,Box} in GrlMedia; It should also help us to identify problems with media types that were not originally supported, such as #767182</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Nothing like talking about Grilo to keep the blog going and to be honest I have some interesting things to talk about.
Grilo 0.3 The major release happened almost 6 months ago and it has brought some API/ABI changes being my favourite the merge of all Grilo media types into GrlMedia (#755551); This introduces support from Grilo to different types of media!
Well, to be pedantic, it was always possible to have different media types in Grilo on GrlMedia but it is more clear to applications by merging GrlMedia{Audio,Video,Image,Box} in GrlMedia; It should also help us to identify problems with media types that were not originally supported, such as #767182
I expect this change will increase the interest in Grilo for a whole new set of applications. For instance, with TheGamesDB source we got support to metadata for Games (#766678) and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see how Kekun will be using this in the gnome-games project!
Plugins A few other plugins have landed upstream as well. I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned TheGamesDB before but we also have iTunes Podcast, both written by Bastien.
I was able to finally finish a plugin related to my GSoC in 2014: AcoustID. In the end, we decided to split the audio decoding and the audio&amp;rsquo;s fingerprint generation in one plugin called Chromaprint and another plugin that actually fetch data on AcoustID web service.
It took some time and the learning process was quite great by learning GStreamer from scratch. As always, many thanks to Bastien for the guidance and also to thiagoss by helping out with the GStreamer bits :-)
PS: Three of the four plugins above were written in Lua :-)
Google Summer of Code 2016 And we already are in the development phase of GSoC 2016! As always, exciting projects in GNOME.
I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in Music this year. Gaurav Narula is working to have ownCloud Support and Saiful Khan will be making Audio Tag Editing possible from Music. The #gnome-music channel has been quite active by having interesting and amusing discussions. I guess this will be a good year for Music.
Big expectations as well with Alexandru Visarion working on Boxes in order to have More Spice Features - Yay! It was sheer coincidence as today we were discussing about shared folders with Spice&amp;rsquo;s webdav. That will be great to land in Boxes!
I wish all the students a great learning experience.
Other news Grilo has piqued my interest since before 2013 as neat project that I could be using in one Set-Top Box that I had in hands; it then became the project for my first free software contribution; it has been nearly two years since my second GSoC but I&amp;rsquo;m still having fun with Grilo.
So, you could imagine how happy I am to become co-maintainer to this great project :)
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Grilo framework and Lua</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/talks/1601/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 12:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/talks/1601/</guid>
        <description>The DevConf CZ is a three-day conference that brings different communities of developers together in Brno, Czech Republic. Organized by Red Hat, this conference offers several interesting topics on talks or workshops. Great to keep yourself up-to-date on fast evolving technologies.
My collegues presented Spice on Windows describing the process to deliver Windows builds of SPICE components from a Linux machine. As extra, Virgl &#43; Spice (Linux-only) was showed in the end, check it out!</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[The DevConf CZ is a three-day conference that brings different communities of developers together in Brno, Czech Republic. Organized by Red Hat, this conference offers several interesting topics on talks or workshops. Great to keep yourself up-to-date on fast evolving technologies.
My collegues presented Spice on Windows describing the process to deliver Windows builds of SPICE components from a Linux machine. As extra, Virgl &#43; Spice (Linux-only) was showed in the end, check it out!
As SPICE was covered by very capable hands, I talked about Grilo once again but covering it all the way from application side using Grilo core and the the usage and development of Grilo plugins.
Video Slides
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One year</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1501/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 23:34:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1501/</guid>
        <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost one year since my last blog post. One year since I got married and left Brazil to live in Czech Republic. In my last post I talked about all the changes I was passing through but no change is bigger than having a baby. Tereza has almost 4 months now :)
One year at Red Hat and Spice.
Even with the great amount of things to do in personal and professional life, I want to keep making GNOME better as much as I can in my free time and thus I want to get back to blogging again.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[It&amp;rsquo;s been almost one year since my last blog post. One year since I got married and left Brazil to live in Czech Republic. In my last post I talked about all the changes I was passing through but no change is bigger than having a baby. Tereza has almost 4 months now :)
One year at Red Hat and Spice.
Even with the great amount of things to do in personal and professional life, I want to keep making GNOME better as much as I can in my free time and thus I want to get back to blogging again.
I&amp;rsquo;ve finally managed to migrate from Blogger to Pelican so I hope that more personal posts like this one will not be part of Planet GNOME in the future :)
I also plan to blog more about personal stuff such as being a father or living abroad. I hope that it can ease the distance from family and friends in Brazil.
This one year was just crazy. Time flies and nothing like raising a child to realize that.
Cheers!
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello new life</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1408/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 21:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1408/</guid>
        <description>Since the end of the Google Summer of Code 2014 so many things have happened that It is really hard to make a simple blog post about it&amp;hellip; but I must try :)
New job Well, along with the GSoC I&amp;rsquo;ve applied to a job at Red Hat and the process ended in August. Since October 15th I am part of the Spice team and I will be working at the Brno office in Czech Republic.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Since the end of the Google Summer of Code 2014 so many things have happened that It is really hard to make a simple blog post about it&amp;hellip; but I must try :)
New job Well, along with the GSoC I&amp;rsquo;ve applied to a job at Red Hat and the process ended in August. Since October 15th I am part of the Spice team and I will be working at the Brno office in Czech Republic.
I am really excited with the work and with the team. I am learning a lot already.
New City I have visited Brno at GUADEC 2013, lovely city. I feel safe here unlike Campinas in Brazil.
I have great expectations about living here and so do my wife after reading Christian&amp;rsquo;s blog post about leaving Brno.
Married Yay ;) Yes, biggest decision of my life.
We have been together for almost three years now and we were living together for almost one year which made this decision straightforward for me. Catielle is a wonderful person and I am really happy with our marriage. I feel that we are going to be very happy here in Brno.
Pending Well, I was quite a busy in the last two months but I still have a lot of things to do!
A few blog posts about GUADEC, GSoC and Grilo I want to move this Blog to Pelican :-) Finishing off a few things related to the last GSoC project, making it upstream! Writing a documentation for the lua-factory plugin :-)
That&amp;rsquo;s all for now! I will be back hacking and blogging now that things are getting calmer.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another GSoC on Grilo!</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/talks/1401/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/talks/1401/</guid>
        <description>GUADEC 2014 took place in Strasbourg, France and that was my first time in this beautiful country. My friend Watson Sato was also enrolled in the GSoC on GNOME and we were able to travel and attend the conference together.
The time slot per intern for the light talk was very short once again but everybody was able to summarize their work very well. Sadly the video was not uploaded.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[GUADEC 2014 took place in Strasbourg, France and that was my first time in this beautiful country. My friend Watson Sato was also enrolled in the GSoC on GNOME and we were able to travel and attend the conference together.
The time slot per intern for the light talk was very short once again but everybody was able to summarize their work very well. Sadly the video was not uploaded.
I hope to come back to visit France more times in the future.
Slides
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Report #6 and #7</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1407/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 02:58:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1407/</guid>
        <description>Tuesday&amp;hellip; Two weeks without posting again! Can I use as an excuse my grief for Brazil in this World Cup!? :) Well, actually I was somewhat busy studying&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll share what in a moment.
In order to talk about what I&amp;rsquo;m working on I would like to explain one interesting feature that Grilo has.
Cool thing in Grilo? You may know that Grilo uses plugins to fetch useful data to your application!</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Tuesday&amp;hellip; Two weeks without posting again! Can I use as an excuse my grief for Brazil in this World Cup!? :) Well, actually I was somewhat busy studying&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll share what in a moment.
In order to talk about what I&amp;rsquo;m working on I would like to explain one interesting feature that Grilo has.
Cool thing in Grilo? You may know that Grilo uses plugins to fetch useful data to your application! Great. What you may not know is that Grilo can combine the use of its plugins to resolve what the application want!
Let me explain.
The TVDB can provide tons of interesting metadata for your TV Shows but to do so, It needs some keys in order to find your TV Show in its database like the name of the show the season and the episode that you are watching.
Cool thing that there is a Grilo plugin called local-metadata which try to get as much data as possible from the file name. For instance, It is easy to local-metadata to gather all metadata necessary to The TVDB from files like:
Boardwalk.Empire.S04E01.HDTV.x264-2HD.mp4; Adventure Time - 2x01 - It Came from the Nightosphere.mp4 etc&amp;hellip;
MusicBrainz Well, I&amp;rsquo;ll be working in a MusicBrainz plugin to Grilo which will be very useful for several applications indeed. But from a music file, how you identify Author, Artist or anything?
One cool way is checking the audio fingerprint!
AcoustID has an Open database accessible through a webservice to get the MusicBrainz Track ID from your audio fingerprint!
So, this is pretty much similar of the example above with the TVDB and local-metadata. The AcoustID will provide the MusicBrainz ID of the track and the MusicBrainz plugin will use this to get all metadata necessary. Cool, right?
Out of curiosity I read this awesome blog post which explains how the fingerprint are calculated and how the AcoustID use that to search in its database. Check it out!
AcoustID 1&amp;frasl;2 So, in order to generate the fingerprint as AcoustID needs, It is necessary to read the entire music file while providing the raw data to the chromaprint library.
My first attempt to do that was using the libraries of ffmpeg as I already had some background with it and also a functional-example in hands.
Of course it was a bad decision to implement such thing without talking with Bastien first :)
He has explained a bit of the problems of having ffmpeg as dependency&amp;hellip;
AcoustID 2&amp;frasl;2 Then I started doing one thing that I was postponing for some time: learning GStreamer.
I read the manual and in its examples in order to understand how it works and what would be the best way to implement the AcoustID.
In the end, there was already a Chromaprint plugin!
The result is smaller but faster application then my previous work with ffmpeg :-)
You can check the current AcoustID plugin here.
Okay and what about that GNOME Video UI Well, yes. I&amp;rsquo;m trying.
The current code is here, seriously, I want to make this work with CSS but somehow it is not working properly.
For instance, I can change the attributes for all GtkLabel but I can&amp;rsquo;t change a specific GtkLabel alone.
I can&amp;rsquo;t tell how glad I was after checking the GUADEC schedule and see the &amp;quot;GTK and CSS&amp;quot; talk from Benjamin Otte. I&amp;rsquo;ll be there, for sure!
I think that&amp;rsquo;s all folks,
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC Report #4 and #5</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1406/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 23:34:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1406/</guid>
        <description>Hey :) I usually write my posts in the weekend when I do have more time to think about what I&amp;rsquo;ve done and what It is interesting to share. Sadly, two weekends ago I was ill due something I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten and now I&amp;rsquo;ll try to summarize two weeks in one post!
The TVDB Is now upstream. Yay!
The main care after implementing the cache with Gom was handling multiple requests of the same TV Show in a short period of time (concurrency).</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Hey :) I usually write my posts in the weekend when I do have more time to think about what I&amp;rsquo;ve done and what It is interesting to share. Sadly, two weekends ago I was ill due something I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten and now I&amp;rsquo;ll try to summarize two weeks in one post!
The TVDB Is now upstream. Yay!
The main care after implementing the cache with Gom was handling multiple requests of the same TV Show in a short period of time (concurrency).
For instance, you are browsing some TV Show using some application that uses Grilo to requests metadata. It may occur several requests of the same tv show like, episode 01, episode 02, etc.
We are handling this by fetching the TVDB only once to gather all existing data and then resolve the later requests with the cache.
Quite nice, lots of fun implementing it.
The Integration with the UI I have realized I&amp;rsquo;m really bad at building UIs and I&amp;rsquo;m also recognizing how much effort it is necessary to make a good UI (a lot).
For that, I would like to thank the folks from Glade with the awesome and helpful software.
Well, at the moment I&amp;rsquo;m implementing a simple program that creates a Widget to show all interesting information we will be providing on GNOME Videos. You may check the application here.
The goal: Current status Life World cup is going on, traffic jam everywhere but people are in quite good mood here in Brazil. I&amp;rsquo;m happier mostly because of my new great friend, Marvin.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC 2014 Report #3 - gom</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1405/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 02:04:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1405/</guid>
        <description>gom Most of the work I&amp;rsquo;ve being doing since last report is improving the TVDB source in Grilo Plugins in order to have a cache for all data that you have once downloaded from thetvdb.com.
I&amp;rsquo;m doing that with gom.
At first I thought it was a bit complicated as creating sql queries directly is easier. But under the hood gom does a lot of useful things that you don&amp;rsquo;t even need to bother thinking.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ gom Most of the work I&amp;rsquo;ve being doing since last report is improving the TVDB source in Grilo Plugins in order to have a cache for all data that you have once downloaded from thetvdb.com.
I&amp;rsquo;m doing that with gom.
At first I thought it was a bit complicated as creating sql queries directly is easier. But under the hood gom does a lot of useful things that you don&amp;rsquo;t even need to bother thinking. It is good to see that it was moved to git.gnome.org.
Also, It was really good to see Magnatune working when I was reading the last post from Sai. It was my first patch to GNOME :). I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about updating the Magnatune source with gom in the near future and probably with more features. Let&amp;rsquo;s see!
Note: One could check the thetvdb source patches here.
Next The integration with GNOME Videos! I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see this working :)
Guadec Oh yeah! I loved last year conference and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss this year. Thanks very much to the GNOME Foundation for helping out with the sponsorship.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC 2014 Report #2 - The TVDB - Tests and Libs</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1404/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 01:58:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1404/</guid>
        <description>Keep moving! One of the great features of the TVDB is all the image gallery that they have and provide. To get as much interesting data as possible using Grilo we need to extend our source and a great way to do it is through creating custom metadata-keys.
With these newly created metadata-keys the TVDB source can now provide an url to the most voted Fanart, Poster and Banner of the tv show.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Keep moving! One of the great features of the TVDB is all the image gallery that they have and provide. To get as much interesting data as possible using Grilo we need to extend our source and a great way to do it is through creating custom metadata-keys.
With these newly created metadata-keys the TVDB source can now provide an url to the most voted Fanart, Poster and Banner of the tv show.
Tests I had included a few tests in the first week but it was just to show that the source was usable. The current version of the tests check if the source is finding the right data in a resolve operation.
Simple enough but helped a lot finding bugs already :)
Libs Well, I thought it would be nice to point a few libraries that I have never used before implementing this source:
 Libxml: Yes, never! I always choose JSON when available! :) The library has a nice documentation with samples but what really helped me was others sources in Grilo. I&amp;rsquo;ve also realized that I&amp;rsquo;m not big fan of camelCase. Libarchive: I&amp;rsquo;ve come to know about this library in Planet feed when Bastien posted about it. Currently it is also included in Lua-Factory with a function which provides &amp;lsquo;unzip&amp;rsquo; to lua-sources in Grilo. Quite awesome. Libgom: Awesome but not very easy. The examples and the blog posts are the best documentation. I&amp;rsquo;ve started with a simple DB and at this moment I&amp;rsquo;m envolving from there before applying it to the TVDB.  Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;m going to finish the coding of the TVDB source soon enough and then I&amp;rsquo;ll be starting the integration with Totem GNOME Videos. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to see all work combined.
Relax Beautiful GNOME-shaped soap. Smells so good!
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC 2014 Report #1 - The TVDB</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1403/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 23:34:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1403/</guid>
        <description>Start This is the first weekend since the beginning of GSoC coding period and it has been satisfactory. For those that have no clue on what I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on this summer, part of it is implementing TV Shows support in GNOME Videos!
In order to provide all information necessary to the interface, we will be using Grilo with the The TVDB source which is what I&amp;rsquo;m working on at the moment.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Start This is the first weekend since the beginning of GSoC coding period and it has been satisfactory. For those that have no clue on what I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on this summer, part of it is implementing TV Shows support in GNOME Videos!
In order to provide all information necessary to the interface, we will be using Grilo with the The TVDB source which is what I&amp;rsquo;m working on at the moment.
The TVDB The TVDB is an &amp;amp;quot;open database for television fans&amp;amp;quot; and it is just awesome. This database provides tons of information and images of series and episodes in several languages. It is a great source for Grilo and will fulfill completely our need.
I strongly recommend a little browsing in the image gallery which has banners, fan art, posters like House, Breaking Bad. They have animes too like Naruto or Evangelion.
Grilo Source: grl-thetvdb The first version is up on bugzilla not ready to upstream yet but it is functional. At this stage I&amp;rsquo;m not holding the data locally in any form. Every time the application request something to grl-thetvdb it will fetch the data from thetvdb.com which is poor design.
But thats all I&amp;rsquo;ve got for this first week!
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Summer of Code 2014</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1402/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 23:43:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1402/</guid>
        <description>Another great summer is coming I was accepted, once again, at Google Summer of Code program! I am really excited with the project. I&amp;rsquo;ll have fun with Grilo again by implementing a few new plugins and integrating them to Videos and Music.
Check the wiki of the project for more info.
Many thanks to Google for this amazing program and to Bastien, which will be mentoring me during this period.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Another great summer is coming I was accepted, once again, at Google Summer of Code program! I am really excited with the project. I&amp;rsquo;ll have fun with Grilo again by implementing a few new plugins and integrating them to Videos and Music.
Check the wiki of the project for more info.
Many thanks to Google for this amazing program and to Bastien, which will be mentoring me during this period.
Partner in this Summer of Coding! Once again we have two brazilians in the GNOME-SoC, me and my great friend Watson Sato (yuuma)! He&amp;rsquo;ll be working in a security module to Evolution. Good luck!
So, Let&amp;rsquo;s have fun!
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lua-Factory available upstream</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1401/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:19:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1401/</guid>
        <description>It has been four months since the GSoC 2013 code submission. At that time the Lua-Factory Plugin was usable but yet with some issues to be dealt.
It was in the last two weeks that most of those issues were solved together with a few recommendations from Juan and Bastien and tonight it was merged upstream in Grilo-Plugins repository.
Hooray!
The documentation for implementing a Lua sources will come soon.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ It has been four months since the GSoC 2013 code submission. At that time the Lua-Factory Plugin was usable but yet with some issues to be dealt.
It was in the last two weeks that most of those issues were solved together with a few recommendations from Juan and Bastien and tonight it was merged upstream in Grilo-Plugins repository.
Hooray!
The documentation for implementing a Lua sources will come soon.
If you want to try it, you can always find some guidance in #grilo channel.
News from Brazil It is Carnaval!
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC last week, GNOME final report! :)</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1307/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:34:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1307/</guid>
        <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last post just after GUADEC. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost some time in August due moving to a new place in Campinas with two friends of mine. It was three weeks ago and I&amp;rsquo;m still feeling tired (I&amp;rsquo;m taking some time to get used with this new place).
Since then, I&amp;rsquo;m working on grilo-plugins and this post is all about what I&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished and what are the next steps after GSoC.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last post just after GUADEC. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost some time in August due moving to a new place in Campinas with two friends of mine. It was three weeks ago and I&amp;rsquo;m still feeling tired (I&amp;rsquo;m taking some time to get used with this new place).
Since then, I&amp;rsquo;m working on grilo-plugins and this post is all about what I&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished and what are the next steps after GSoC.
(The post is bigger then usual so&amp;hellip; grab a cup of coffee !) As I told before, Grilo has some commands that are translated to the source like Search and Browse operations. Good part of my project was translating this commands from Grilo to the Lua source and the result of this work was the lua-factory plugin.
The subset of commands available to Lua sources are: Search, Browse, Query, Resolve, May Resolve, Store and Remove. I&amp;rsquo;ve developed two Lua sources that implement those commands besides the last two (Store and Remove) due a library dependency that will be commented bellow.
Those Lua sources are Metrolyrics and Flickr which already exists as C source.
Due the limitations of the standards libraries of Lua and the need of interaction with Grilo itself the lua library was created. This is a set of lua modules that are helpful for the developers. Those modules could be wrappers of C librarys or custom functions.
For instance, to be able to interact with Flickr web service a wrapper of oauth library was created;
And all this were just the first steps;
Current issues that should be improved The main goal of the GSoC project was being able to write plugins with Lua and them should be transparent to Grilo, making no difference between a C or Lua source. I feel that was accomplished but no without problems, lets check some of them 1:
 The annoying userdata: To perform the callback from Lua source to the Application, we need to store the userdata passed from lua-factory somehow. There are a couple of ways of doing it but I didn&amp;rsquo;t made it work before GUADEC and it was kind of low priority after; For instance, the Search operation in Lua should be a function called grl_source_search() wich have two parameters: (1) a Table with the data that the functions need; (2) An userdata which is a pointer to a structure in C (which is no useful for Lua code); A better approach is storing this in the Lua stack, hiding from lua code;
 Improving the GrlNet library with the possibility to POST content to the web. This was the reason that I didn&amp;rsquo;t implement Store and Remove in the Lua Flickr source :(
 A better callback implementation (or a totally different one). This is one of the topics I talked with Juan in GUADEC and this could actually be expanded to Grilo itself so, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it to another post;
 More sources! In order to be sure that this code is trustable a few more sources are needed; They will be implemented after the two first topics! 2)
  The last week of GSoC Period This week I&amp;rsquo;m not writing much code but trying to make a useful documentation to help other developers.
But as we can see in google&amp;rsquo;s timeline, next week I&amp;rsquo;ll be submitting the source code I&amp;rsquo;ve developed so far.
It will be the last week of GSoC but not my last in Grilo or in this project. Hopefully, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a few more improvements in the end of October!
A big thanks to Juan for all the feedback, help and insights! I&amp;rsquo;ve made big steps these last three months and you help me out everytime :)
Final considerations I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed a lot this period! I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt a lot! I&amp;rsquo;ve met amazing people! I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled more then 10&amp;rsquo;000Km to a beautiful city to attend a super conference! I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt Lua (and loving it!)
I&amp;rsquo;m lucky. Thanks to GNOME and Google for that!
Wow, you made it till here. You can reclaim a beer in the next GUADEC!
Did you know ? Grilo is a type of bug in Brazil ? A Cricket !
 If the reader see more problems not listed, feel free to comment it! ↩ If the reader want to see a source implemented to Grilo, tell me! I&amp;rsquo;m kind of building a small list :)
↩   ]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brno, GUADEC and Grilo</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1306/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 22:21:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1306/</guid>
        <description>Brno is amazing. Just amazing. The people from here try to be helpfull even if they don&amp;rsquo;t speak a single word in English. The food is really good and quite cheap and the city is beautiful! I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I still have time for another tour around!
Well, travelling without many concerns, meeting amazing people and with the opportunity to learn things you love&amp;hellip; GUADEC has been an amazing experience.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Brno is amazing. Just amazing. The people from here try to be helpfull even if they don&amp;rsquo;t speak a single word in English. The food is really good and quite cheap and the city is beautiful! I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I still have time for another tour around!
Well, travelling without many concerns, meeting amazing people and with the opportunity to learn things you love&amp;hellip; GUADEC has been an amazing experience.
The talks were really good but the people I have met here are awesome.
I&amp;rsquo;m really glad to finally meet my mentor Juan Suárez and some folks from Red Hat. It was awesome to talk with some others interns such as Kalev, Marcos, Valentín, Alessandro, Bogdan and Carlos. It was brief but really nice. Hope to meet everybody again next year!
Here in GUADEC I had a lightning talk trying to briefly explain what my GSoC is about. It was hard to do it in less then 3 minutes. I was quite nervous too but everything went well :)
If anybody would like to know more about grilo or anything related ping me on #grilo
I had the opportunity to talk with Juan about the GSoC project, Grilo and some plans for the future. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit excited to keep contributing to Grilo.
I would like to thank GNOME Fundation for the sponsorship and making this travel possible; to Google for the Summer of Code Program; to Fabiano Fidêncio for helping me A LOT in Brno.
And that&amp;rsquo;s all.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My GSOC on Grilo!</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/talks/1301/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 16:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/talks/1301/</guid>
        <description>GUADEC 2013 was hosted in Brno, Czech Republic and it was my first time doing a talk for a big audience, quite an experience! I can see how nervous I got in the two minutes I had for the interns lightning talk.
Not super instructive video to watch but quite funny to me :)
Also, It is very interesting that a little bit more then a year later, I would be moving to Brno to start a new phase of my life.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[GUADEC 2013 was hosted in Brno, Czech Republic and it was my first time doing a talk for a big audience, quite an experience! I can see how nervous I got in the two minutes I had for the interns lightning talk.
Not super instructive video to watch but quite funny to me :)
Also, It is very interesting that a little bit more then a year later, I would be moving to Brno to start a new phase of my life.
Video Slides
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The unpredictable, GSoC report and next steps</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1305/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 22:56:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1305/</guid>
        <description>Oh boy, there are things that can slow you down. It&amp;rsquo;s been three weeks since my last post, in this short period of time I had a car accident ( I&amp;rsquo;m 100% alright! ), one root canal treatment (with a good dose of pain), my girlfriend moved to another city&amp;hellip; Oh well, too many headaches in three weeks!
But when I was in good mood (or healthy enough) here I was, in front of this screen trying to make good code to Grilo&amp;hellip; and I like the achievements so far.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Oh boy, there are things that can slow you down. It&amp;rsquo;s been three weeks since my last post, in this short period of time I had a car accident ( I&amp;rsquo;m 100% alright! ), one root canal treatment (with a good dose of pain), my girlfriend moved to another city&amp;hellip; Oh well, too many headaches in three weeks!
But when I was in good mood (or healthy enough) here I was, in front of this screen trying to make good code to Grilo&amp;hellip; and I like the achievements so far. Lets take a look.
I started to implement the Metrolyrics plugin before writing any C code to Grilo in order to have a lua-based plugin to use. A lot of this plugin has changed to work with lua-factory. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t remember, lua-factory is part of grilo-plugins, and it is the glue-code in charge to load-and-use the lua-plugins.
In this moment, we can use the Search, Browse, Query and Resolve operations from Grilo to this lua-plugin.
As the lua code needs some help from C to perform a few operations, lua-library was created to be a module to lua. This module has two functions implemented: Fetch, to perform async fetch from web and Callback, to return the content to the application.
A lot has to be done yet. Hopefully without any personal headache :)
For instance:
 Store and Remove operations must be implemented in lua-factory; Log and Error functions to the lua-library; Better care with user configs, metadata-keys Solving some problems with UTF-8 chars  I will be writing a new lua-plugin this week and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to choose between Soundcloud or Last.fm. Both have the necessary features to be implemented that Metrolyrics lacks for Grilo.
Well, I intend to make my next post in Brno before GUADEC and another post after with much more GNOMExperience&amp;hellip;
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Planet, GSoC project and Brazil</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1304/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 02:14:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1304/</guid>
        <description>First of all, hello everybody from Planet Gnome! This is the first post that will take place there. It is a really nice community where I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning always something new from the past 5 months. I hope I can put some interesting hacks for you guys.
Thank you Alberto Ruiz for including me.
I was accepted in GSoC this year to be working with Grilo. It is a really nice project which I&amp;rsquo;m always having some fun while coding.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[First of all, hello everybody from Planet Gnome! This is the first post that will take place there. It is a really nice community where I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning always something new from the past 5 months. I hope I can put some interesting hacks for you guys.
Thank you Alberto Ruiz for including me.
I was accepted in GSoC this year to be working with Grilo. It is a really nice project which I&amp;rsquo;m always having some fun while coding. I&amp;rsquo;m being mentored by Juan Suarez who has been always helpful with my problems.
Grilo is basically a framework to get content through plugins. A lot of plugins were made already and all were written in C. My GSoC project is about making possible to write plugins in Lua.
About the project itself, I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing a glue-code between Grilo and Lua. They&amp;rsquo;ll be tagged as lua-factory as the c code dealing with lua; and grilo-library as a library written in c to be used by the lua-plugins.
I tried to make a simple design to represent how grilo and grilo-plugins works now and where my code will take place.
The &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; is one of the subset commands that Grilo can request.
The progress in the moment I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post is that the lyric plugin get the content (by &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;browse&amp;rsquo;) and I&amp;rsquo;m able to load the plugin with my current lua-factory but can&amp;rsquo;t perform any command yet.
I guest this is it about GSoC for now :)
I would also like to say to those who followed me here, we have at least three Brazilians interns in GNOME this year: Rafael Fonseca, Melissa Wen and myself. Brazil is in such crazy historical moment right now.
If you know absolute nothing about it please do :)
To finish this post, this beautiful GNOME cup that my girlfriend gave to me in my birthday.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lua, Lyrics and GUADEC</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1303/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 03:01:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1303/</guid>
        <description>First of all, as a good beginner in blogging I have promised that
I&#39;ll make a proper introducing of the project later this week  which I did not. Sorry for that. I hope to do it soon.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying Lua since last weekend with the good guidance of the Programming in Lua (written by Roberto Ierusalimschy as a way to improve my lua skills. Actually, before starting reading this book I thought my knowledge of lua was _[ok]() because it is easy to understand and make some code.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[First of all, as a good beginner in blogging I have promised that
I&#39;ll make a proper introducing of the project later this week  which I did not. Sorry for that. I hope to do it soon.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying Lua since last weekend with the good guidance of the Programming in Lua (written by Roberto Ierusalimschy as a way to improve my lua skills. Actually, before starting reading this book I thought my knowledge of lua was _[ok]() because it is easy to understand and make some code. Naive!
Lua is simple but we can do a lot with it. The book is helping me to really understand how powerful Lua can be. Actually, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that all I&amp;rsquo;m learning is necessary to implement plugins. I keep studying because I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying Lua. :)
I&amp;rsquo;ve started the lua-plugin that I&amp;rsquo;ll be using in the next steps of my GSoC project. It&amp;rsquo;ll be about Lyrics, using an available API of Metrolyrics. This plugin will help me for the next 4 weeks or so with a subset of Grilo functions.
Good news is that I&amp;rsquo;ll attend to GUADEC in Brno, Czech Republic in August. It will be an amazing trip and I&amp;rsquo;ll hopefully meet some of the people that helped me to achieve all this.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Magnatune upstream and GSoC</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1302/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:57:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1302/</guid>
        <description>I was having a busy week until this Sunday which happened to be my birthday!
I just made 25 years old and the celebration with my family was remarkable.
I&amp;rsquo;m just happy with such great family.
But besides my family, two amazing things made this last three days quite unforgettable.
First, my first code to an open source community reached the upstream! As posted by Juan, within the 0.2.8 release of grilo-plugins is included the Magnatune plugin.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[I was having a busy week until this Sunday which happened to be my birthday!
I just made 25 years old and the celebration with my family was remarkable.
I&amp;rsquo;m just happy with such great family.
But besides my family, two amazing things made this last three days quite unforgettable.
First, my first code to an open source community reached the upstream! As posted by Juan, within the 0.2.8 release of grilo-plugins is included the Magnatune plugin.
I&amp;rsquo;m really glad about it! Thanks to Juan and Bastien for all suggestions and for reviewing the patches!
Second, I was accepted at Google Summer of Code program to keep working with grilo! I&amp;rsquo;ll make a proper introducing of the project later this week but the reader can have an idea at the abstract page.
Thanks to GNOME and Google for it.
 A lot is happening and I&amp;rsquo;m full of good expectations.  :)
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Step by step</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1301/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:02:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1301/</guid>
        <description>Time goes by when you finally finish your 18 years studying things that people said you need to learn. Finally you start doing more and more things that you want to do. Learning what you think is interesting and working with what you love.
I&amp;rsquo;m entering in a new phase of my life.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working in a few projects that made most of my days goes by in a blink of an eye.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Time goes by when you finally finish your 18 years studying things that people said you need to learn. Finally you start doing more and more things that you want to do. Learning what you think is interesting and working with what you love.
I&amp;rsquo;m entering in a new phase of my life.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working in a few projects that made most of my days goes by in a blink of an eye. Which is something that would make most of us really happy.
But it was recently that I felt a different kind of happiness with my work.
I was studying how Grilo works to use it in small project of mine.
Out of curiosity, I began to have more interest in how exactly Grilo works and the features that were expected to its future. It was about time to GSoC period start and I felt quite comfortable at seeking guidance with Grilo developers to share my will to help.
A little more than a month since my first contact with the community and I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to make some code reach upstream a plugin but&amp;hellip; what amazing experience this has been!
I didn&amp;rsquo;t know Magnatune until Juan introducing it to me. It&amp;rsquo;s really nice (check it out).
Even if some audio players have already a good Magnatune plugin (like Rhythmbox), the plugin I&amp;rsquo;m working on could be useful for others applications that may be integrated with Grilo.
The feeling of usefulness that I rarely felt with others projects I have worked, I found after this time I&amp;rsquo;ve spent with Grilo.
I&amp;rsquo;m really excited with all this. I&amp;rsquo;m learning a lot and I truly believe that I can help a lot more.
Step by step, giving back to the community what I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for so many years!
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Victor Toso</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/about/</link>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/about/</guid>
        <description>I am Brazilian by birth (from São Paulo) and Italian due my ancestry. I am living in Brno - Czech Republic with my family. Here I work at Red Hat in the Spice project together with the Desktop team.
I try to manage my time by having fun with my family and working in projects that excites me. I&amp;rsquo;m always interested in the great game of Go (even though I&amp;rsquo;m weak) and also do-it-yourself and woodworking projects (even though I&amp;rsquo;m not doing much myself).</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ I am Brazilian by birth (from São Paulo) and Italian due my ancestry. I am living in Brno - Czech Republic with my family. Here I work at Red Hat in the Spice project together with the Desktop team.
I try to manage my time by having fun with my family and working in projects that excites me. I&amp;rsquo;m always interested in the great game of Go (even though I&amp;rsquo;m weak) and also do-it-yourself and woodworking projects (even though I&amp;rsquo;m not doing much myself).
This blog is about me sharing information related to projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on although I plan to share travel and family information so my friends and family in Brazil can lighten the distance a bit.
I&amp;rsquo;m mostly interested in projects related to multimedia and virtualization but also GNOME which is where all the fun happens.
Note: This blog is also my playground to play with web related technologies when I&amp;rsquo;m wiling or due any random necessity.
Contact  Email: toso [at] posteo [dot] net IRC: As toso in gimpnet and freenode Keybase: toso PGP key: 97D9 123D E37A 484F  Social As victortoso in twitter GitLab GitHub
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
