<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Victor Toso</title>
        <link>https%3A//victortoso.com</link>
        <description>Nothing relevant</description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="https%3A//victortoso.com/tags/gnome/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Google Summer of Code 2014</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1402/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1402/</guid>
                <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;another-great-summer-is-coming&quot;&gt;Another great summer is coming&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was accepted, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.victortoso.com&#x2F;magnatune-upstream-and-gsoc.html&quot;&gt;once
again&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, at
Google Summer of Code program! I am really excited with the project.
I&#x27;ll have fun with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;live.gnome.org&#x2F;Grilo&quot;&gt;Grilo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; again by
implementing a few new plugins and integrating them to Videos and Music.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.gnome.org&#x2F;Outreach&#x2F;SummerOfCode&#x2F;2014&#x2F;Projects&#x2F;VictorToso_VideosAndMusicWithGrilo&quot;&gt;wiki of the
project&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
for more info.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to Google for this amazing program and to
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.gnome.org&#x2F;BastienNocera&quot;&gt;Bastien&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which will be mentoring
me during this period.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;partner-in-this-summer-of-coding&quot;&gt;Partner in this Summer of Coding!&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again we have two brazilians in the GNOME-SoC, me and my great
friend Watson Sato
(&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.gnome.org&#x2F;Outreach&#x2F;SummerOfCode&#x2F;2014&#x2F;Projects&#x2F;YuumaSato_Pkcs11ModuleEvolution&quot;&gt;yuuma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)!
He&#x27;ll be working in a security module to Evolution. Good luck!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Let&#x27;s have fun!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>GSoC last week, GNOME final report! :)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1307/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1307/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s been a while since my last post just after GUADEC. I&#x27;ve lost some
time in August due moving to a new place in Campinas with two friends of
mine. It was three weeks ago and I&#x27;m still feeling tired (I&#x27;m taking
some time to get used with this new place).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, I&#x27;m working on grilo-plugins and this post is all about what
I&#x27;ve accomplished and what are the next steps after GSoC.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-post-is-bigger-then-usual-so-grab-a-cup-of-coffee&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;(The post is bigger then usual so... grab a cup of coffee !)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.victortoso.com&#x2F;planet-gsoc-project-and-brazil.html&quot;&gt;I told
before&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
Grilo has some commands that are translated to the source like Search
and Browse operations. Good part of my project was translating this
commands from Grilo to the Lua source and the result of this work was
the lua-factory plugin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subset of commands available to Lua sources are: Search, Browse,
Query, Resolve, May Resolve, Store and Remove. I&#x27;ve developed two Lua
sources that implement those commands besides the last two (Store and
Remove) due a library dependency that will be commented bellow.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those Lua sources are &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.metrolyrics.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Metrolyrics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.flickr.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which already exists as C source.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due the limitations of the standards libraries of Lua and the need of
interaction with Grilo itself the lua library was created. This is a set
of lua modules that are helpful for the developers. Those modules could
be wrappers of C librarys or custom functions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, to be able to interact with Flickr web service a wrapper
of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;OAuth&quot;&gt;oauth&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; library was created;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And all this were just the first steps;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;current-issues-that-should-be-improved&quot;&gt;Current issues that should be improved&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal of the GSoC project was being able to write plugins with
Lua and them should be transparent to Grilo, making no difference
between a C or Lua source. I feel that was accomplished but no without
problems, lets check some of them &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the reader see more problems not listed, feel free to comment it!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The annoying userdata: To perform the callback from Lua source to
the Application, we need to store the userdata passed from
lua-factory somehow. There are a couple of ways of doing it but I
didn&#x27;t made it work before GUADEC and it was kind of low priority
after; For instance, the Search operation in Lua should be a
function called grl_source_search() wich have two parameters:
(1) a Table with the data that the functions need; (2) An userdata which
is a pointer to a structure in C (which is no useful for Lua code); A
better approach is storing this in the Lua stack, hiding from lua code;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improving the GrlNet library with the possibility to POST content to
the web. This was the reason that I didn&#x27;t implement Store and
Remove in the Lua Flickr source :(&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A better callback implementation (or a totally different one). This
is one of the topics I talked with
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.igalia.com&#x2F;nc&#x2F;igalia-247&#x2F;igalian&#x2F;item&#x2F;jasuarez&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Juan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
in GUADEC and this could actually be expanded to Grilo itself so,
I&#x27;ll keep it to another post;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More sources! In order to be sure that this code is trustable a few
more sources are needed; They will be implemented after the two
first topics! &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the reader want to see a source implemented to Grilo,
tell me! I&#x27;m kind of building a small list :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-last-week-of-gsoc-period&quot;&gt;The last week of GSoC Period&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I&#x27;m not writing much code but trying to make a useful
documentation to help other developers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as we can see in google&#x27;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.google-melange.com&#x2F;gsoc&#x2F;events&#x2F;google&#x2F;gsoc2013&quot;&gt;timeline&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
next week I&#x27;ll be submitting the source code I&#x27;ve developed so far.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be the last week of GSoC but not my last in Grilo or in this
project. Hopefully, I&#x27;ll have a few more improvements in the end of
October!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thanks to Juan for all the feedback, help and insights! I&#x27;ve made
big steps these last three months and you help me out everytime :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-considerations&quot;&gt;Final considerations&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve enjoyed a lot this period! I&#x27;ve learnt a lot! I&#x27;ve met amazing
people! I&#x27;ve traveled more then 10&#x27;000Km to a beautiful city to attend a
super conference! I&#x27;ve learnt Lua (and loving it!)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m lucky. Thanks to GNOME and Google for that!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, you made it till here. You can reclaim a beer in the next GUADEC!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know ? Grilo is a type of bug in Brazil ? A Cricket !&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;1307-01-grilo-cricket.png&quot; alt=&quot;Grilo is a bug!&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Brno, GUADEC and Grilo</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1306/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1306/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Brno is amazing. Just amazing. The people from here try to be helpfull
even if they don&#x27;t speak a single word in English. The food is really
good and quite cheap and the city is beautiful! I&#x27;m glad that I still
have time for another tour around!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, travelling without many concerns, meeting amazing people and with
the opportunity to learn things you love... GUADEC has been an amazing
experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talks were really good but the people I have met here are awesome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m really glad to finally meet my mentor Juan Suárez and some folks
from Red Hat. It was awesome to talk with some others interns such as
Kalev, Marcos, Valentín, Alessandro, Bogdan and Carlos. It was brief but
really nice. Hope to meet everybody again next year!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here in GUADEC I had a lightning talk trying to briefly explain what my
GSoC is about. It was hard to do it in less then 3 minutes. I was quite
nervous too but everything went well :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anybody would like to know more about grilo or anything related ping
me on #grilo&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to talk with Juan about the GSoC project, Grilo
and some plans for the future. I&#x27;m a bit excited to keep contributing to
Grilo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank GNOME Fundation for the sponsorship and making
this travel possible; to Google for the Summer of Code Program; to
Fabiano Fidêncio for helping me A LOT in Brno.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#x27;s all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;1306-01-gnome-sponsored-badge.png&quot; alt=&quot;GNOME rocks!&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The unpredictable, GSoC report and next steps</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1305/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1305/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh boy, there are things that can slow you down. It&#x27;s been three weeks
since my last post, in this short period of time I had a car accident (
I&#x27;m 100% alright! ), one root canal treatment (with a good dose of
pain), my girlfriend moved to another city... Oh well, too many
headaches in three weeks!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I was in good mood (or healthy enough) here I was, in front of
this screen trying to make good code to Grilo... and I like the
achievements so far. Lets take a look.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to implement the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.metrolyrics.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Metrolyrics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
plugin before writing any C code to Grilo in order to have a lua-based
plugin to use. A lot of this plugin has changed to work with
lua-factory. For those who &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.victortoso.com&#x2F;planet-gsoc-project-and-brazil.html&quot;&gt;don&#x27;t
remember&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
lua-factory is part of grilo-plugins, and it is the glue-code in charge
to load-and-use the lua-plugins.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this moment, we can use the &lt;em&gt;Search&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Browse&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Query&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Resolve&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
operations from Grilo to this lua-plugin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the lua code needs some help from C to perform a few operations,
lua-library was created to be a module to lua. This module has two
functions implemented: Fetch, to perform async fetch from web and
Callback, to return the content to the application.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot has to be done yet. Hopefully without any personal headache :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Store&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Remove&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; operations must be implemented in lua-factory;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log and Error functions to the lua-library;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better care with user configs, metadata-keys&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solving some problems with UTF-8 chars&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be writing a new lua-plugin this week and I&#x27;m trying to choose
between &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;soundcloud.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Soundcloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.last.fm&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Last.fm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Both have the necessary features to be
implemented that Metrolyrics lacks for Grilo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I intend to make my next post in Brno before GUADEC and another
post after with much more GNOMExperience...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Planet, GSoC project and Brazil</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1304/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1304/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;First of all, hello everybody from Planet Gnome! This is the first post
that will take place there. It is a really nice community where I&#x27;ve
been learning always something new from the past 5 months. I hope I can
put some interesting hacks for you guys.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.gnome.org&#x2F;AlbertoRuiz&quot;&gt;Alberto Ruiz&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for
including me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.victortoso.com&#x2F;magnatune-upstream-and-gsoc.html&quot;&gt;accepted&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
in GSoC this year to be working with
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;live.gnome.org&#x2F;Grilo&quot;&gt;Grilo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It is a really nice project which
I&#x27;m always having some fun while coding. I&#x27;m being mentored by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.gnome.org&#x2F;JuanSuarez&quot;&gt;Juan
Suarez&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who has been always helpful
with my problems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grilo is basically a framework to get content through plugins. A lot of
plugins were made already and all were written in C. My GSoC project is
about making possible to write plugins in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lua.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Lua&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the project itself, I&#x27;ll be writing a glue-code between Grilo and
Lua. They&#x27;ll be tagged as lua-factory as the c code dealing with lua;
and grilo-library as a library written in c to be used by the
lua-plugins.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to make a simple design to represent how grilo and grilo-plugins
works now and where my code will take place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;1304-01-grilo-and-lua-factory.png&quot; alt=&quot;Design of Grilo + Grilo Plugins with Lua-Factory and Lua sources&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &#x27;search&#x27; is one of the subset commands that Grilo can request.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The progress in the moment I&#x27;m writing this post is that the lyric
plugin get the content (by &#x27;search&#x27; and &#x27;browse&#x27;) and I&#x27;m able to load
the plugin with my current lua-factory but can&#x27;t perform any command
yet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guest this is it about GSoC for now :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also like to say to those who followed me here, we have at least
three Brazilians interns in GNOME this year: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;15experience.wordpress.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Rafael
Fonseca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.gnome.org&#x2F;MelissaWen&quot;&gt;Melissa
Wen&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and myself. Brazil is in such
crazy historical moment right now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know absolute nothing about it please do :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish this post, this beautiful GNOME cup that my girlfriend gave to
me in my birthday.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;1304-02-gnome-cup.png&quot; alt=&quot;GNOME cup&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Lua, Lyrics and GUADEC</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1303/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1303/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;First of all, as a good beginner in blogging I have promised that&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;I&amp;#39;ll make a proper introducing of the project later this week
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which I did not. Sorry for that. I hope to do it soon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve been studying Lua since last weekend with the good guidance of the
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lua.org&#x2F;pil&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Programming in Lua&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (written by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.inf.puc-rio.br&#x2F;%7Eroberto&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Roberto
Ierusalimschy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as a way to improve
my lua skills. Actually, before starting reading this book I thought my
knowledge of lua was _&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;victortoso.com&#x2F;blog-1303&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ok&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; because it is easy to understand and make
some code. Naive!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lua is simple but we can do a lot with it. The book is helping me to
really understand how powerful Lua can be. Actually, I don&#x27;t think that
all I&#x27;m learning is necessary to implement plugins. I keep studying
because I&#x27;m enjoying Lua. :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve started the lua-plugin that I&#x27;ll be using in the next steps of my
GSoC project. It&#x27;ll be about Lyrics, using an available API of
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.metrolyrics.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Metrolyrics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This plugin will help me for
the next 4 weeks or so with a subset of Grilo functions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good news is that I&#x27;ll attend to GUADEC in Brno, Czech Republic in
August. It will be an amazing trip and I&#x27;ll hopefully meet some of the
people that helped me to achieve all this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Magnatune upstream and GSoC</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1302/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1302/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was having a busy week until this Sunday which happened to be my
birthday!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just made 25 years old and the celebration with my family was
remarkable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m just happy with such great family.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But besides my family, two amazing things made this last three days
quite unforgettable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, my first code to an open source community reached the upstream!
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;blogs.igalia.com&#x2F;jasuarez&#x2F;2013&#x2F;05&#x2F;25&#x2F;grilo-plugins-0-2-8-released&#x2F;&quot;&gt;As posted by
Juan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
within the 0.2.8 release of grilo-plugins is included the Magnatune
plugin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m really glad about it! Thanks to
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.gnome.org&#x2F;JuanSuarez&quot;&gt;Juan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.gnome.org&#x2F;BastienNocera&quot;&gt;Bastien&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for all suggestions and
for reviewing the patches!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I was accepted at Google Summer of Code program to keep working
with grilo! I&#x27;ll make a proper introducing of the project later this
week but the reader can have an idea at the abstract page.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gnome.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and Google for it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot is happening and I&#x27;m full of good expectations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Step by step</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1301/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1301/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Time goes by when you finally finish your 18 years studying things that
people said you need to learn. Finally you start doing more and more
things that you want to do. Learning what you think is interesting and
working with what you love.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m entering in a new phase of my life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve been working in a few projects that made most of my days goes by in
a blink of an eye. Which is something that would make most of us really
happy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was recently that I felt a different kind of happiness with my
work.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was studying how &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;live.gnome.org&#x2F;Grilo&quot;&gt;Grilo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; works to use it
in small project of mine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of curiosity, I began to have more interest in how exactly Grilo
works and the features that were expected to its future. It was about
time to
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.google-melange.com&#x2F;gsoc&#x2F;homepage&#x2F;google&#x2F;gsoc2013&quot;&gt;GSoC&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
period start and I felt quite comfortable at seeking guidance with Grilo
developers to share my will to help.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little more than a month since my first contact with the community and
I&#x27;m still trying to make some code reach upstream &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bugzilla.gnome.org&#x2F;show_bug.cgi?id=698523&quot;&gt;a
plugin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; but... what
amazing experience this has been!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t know Magnatune until Juan introducing it to me. It&#x27;s really
nice (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;magnatune.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;check it out&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if some audio players have already a good Magnatune plugin (like
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.gnome.org&#x2F;Apps&#x2F;Rhythmbox&quot;&gt;Rhythmbox&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), the plugin I&#x27;m
working on could be useful for others applications that may be
integrated with Grilo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feeling of usefulness that I rarely felt with others projects I have
worked, I found after this time I&#x27;ve spent with Grilo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m really excited with all this. I&#x27;m learning a lot and I truly believe
that I can help a lot more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step by step, giving back to the community what I&#x27;ve been using for so
many years!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
