<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <docs>https://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <title>Lua on Victor Toso</title>
    <link>http://victortoso.com/tags/lua/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lua on Victor Toso</description>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo 0.55.0-DEV</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 02:14:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
      <atom:link href="http://victortoso.com/tags/lua/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Planet, GSoC project and Brazil</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1304/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 02:14:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1304/</guid>
        <description>First of all, hello everybody from Planet Gnome! This is the first post that will take place there. It is a really nice community where I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning always something new from the past 5 months. I hope I can put some interesting hacks for you guys.
Thank you Alberto Ruiz for including me.
I was accepted in GSoC this year to be working with Grilo. It is a really nice project which I&amp;rsquo;m always having some fun while coding.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[First of all, hello everybody from Planet Gnome! This is the first post that will take place there. It is a really nice community where I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning always something new from the past 5 months. I hope I can put some interesting hacks for you guys.
Thank you Alberto Ruiz for including me.
I was accepted in GSoC this year to be working with Grilo. It is a really nice project which I&amp;rsquo;m always having some fun while coding. I&amp;rsquo;m being mentored by Juan Suarez who has been always helpful with my problems.
Grilo is basically a framework to get content through plugins. A lot of plugins were made already and all were written in C. My GSoC project is about making possible to write plugins in Lua.
About the project itself, I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing a glue-code between Grilo and Lua. They&amp;rsquo;ll be tagged as lua-factory as the c code dealing with lua; and grilo-library as a library written in c to be used by the lua-plugins.
I tried to make a simple design to represent how grilo and grilo-plugins works now and where my code will take place.
The &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; is one of the subset commands that Grilo can request.
The progress in the moment I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post is that the lyric plugin get the content (by &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;browse&amp;rsquo;) and I&amp;rsquo;m able to load the plugin with my current lua-factory but can&amp;rsquo;t perform any command yet.
I guest this is it about GSoC for now :)
I would also like to say to those who followed me here, we have at least three Brazilians interns in GNOME this year: Rafael Fonseca, Melissa Wen and myself. Brazil is in such crazy historical moment right now.
If you know absolute nothing about it please do :)
To finish this post, this beautiful GNOME cup that my girlfriend gave to me in my birthday.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lua, Lyrics and GUADEC</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1303/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 03:01:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1303/</guid>
        <description>First of all, as a good beginner in blogging I have promised that
I&#39;ll make a proper introducing of the project later this week  which I did not. Sorry for that. I hope to do it soon.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying Lua since last weekend with the good guidance of the Programming in Lua (written by Roberto Ierusalimschy as a way to improve my lua skills. Actually, before starting reading this book I thought my knowledge of lua was _[ok]() because it is easy to understand and make some code.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[First of all, as a good beginner in blogging I have promised that
I&#39;ll make a proper introducing of the project later this week  which I did not. Sorry for that. I hope to do it soon.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying Lua since last weekend with the good guidance of the Programming in Lua (written by Roberto Ierusalimschy as a way to improve my lua skills. Actually, before starting reading this book I thought my knowledge of lua was _[ok]() because it is easy to understand and make some code. Naive!
Lua is simple but we can do a lot with it. The book is helping me to really understand how powerful Lua can be. Actually, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that all I&amp;rsquo;m learning is necessary to implement plugins. I keep studying because I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying Lua. :)
I&amp;rsquo;ve started the lua-plugin that I&amp;rsquo;ll be using in the next steps of my GSoC project. It&amp;rsquo;ll be about Lyrics, using an available API of Metrolyrics. This plugin will help me for the next 4 weeks or so with a subset of Grilo functions.
Good news is that I&amp;rsquo;ll attend to GUADEC in Brno, Czech Republic in August. It will be an amazing trip and I&amp;rsquo;ll hopefully meet some of the people that helped me to achieve all this.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
