<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <docs>https://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <title>Guadec on Victor Toso</title>
    <link>http://victortoso.com/tags/guadec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guadec on Victor Toso</description>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo 0.55.0-DEV</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 17:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
      <atom:link href="http://victortoso.com/tags/guadec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Another GSoC on Grilo!</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/talks/1401/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/talks/1401/</guid>
        <description>GUADEC 2014 took place in Strasbourg, France and that was my first time in this beautiful country. My friend Watson Sato was also enrolled in the GSoC on GNOME and we were able to travel and attend the conference together.
The time slot per intern for the light talk was very short once again but everybody was able to summarize their work very well. Sadly the video was not uploaded.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[GUADEC 2014 took place in Strasbourg, France and that was my first time in this beautiful country. My friend Watson Sato was also enrolled in the GSoC on GNOME and we were able to travel and attend the conference together.
The time slot per intern for the light talk was very short once again but everybody was able to summarize their work very well. Sadly the video was not uploaded.
I hope to come back to visit France more times in the future.
Slides
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brno, GUADEC and Grilo</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1306/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 22:21:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1306/</guid>
        <description>Brno is amazing. Just amazing. The people from here try to be helpfull even if they don&amp;rsquo;t speak a single word in English. The food is really good and quite cheap and the city is beautiful! I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I still have time for another tour around!
Well, travelling without many concerns, meeting amazing people and with the opportunity to learn things you love&amp;hellip; GUADEC has been an amazing experience.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Brno is amazing. Just amazing. The people from here try to be helpfull even if they don&amp;rsquo;t speak a single word in English. The food is really good and quite cheap and the city is beautiful! I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I still have time for another tour around!
Well, travelling without many concerns, meeting amazing people and with the opportunity to learn things you love&amp;hellip; GUADEC has been an amazing experience.
The talks were really good but the people I have met here are awesome.
I&amp;rsquo;m really glad to finally meet my mentor Juan Suárez and some folks from Red Hat. It was awesome to talk with some others interns such as Kalev, Marcos, Valentín, Alessandro, Bogdan and Carlos. It was brief but really nice. Hope to meet everybody again next year!
Here in GUADEC I had a lightning talk trying to briefly explain what my GSoC is about. It was hard to do it in less then 3 minutes. I was quite nervous too but everything went well :)
If anybody would like to know more about grilo or anything related ping me on #grilo
I had the opportunity to talk with Juan about the GSoC project, Grilo and some plans for the future. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit excited to keep contributing to Grilo.
I would like to thank GNOME Fundation for the sponsorship and making this travel possible; to Google for the Summer of Code Program; to Fabiano Fidêncio for helping me A LOT in Brno.
And that&amp;rsquo;s all.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My GSOC on Grilo!</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/talks/1301/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 16:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/talks/1301/</guid>
        <description>GUADEC 2013 was hosted in Brno, Czech Republic and it was my first time doing a talk for a big audience, quite an experience! I can see how nervous I got in the two minutes I had for the interns lightning talk.
Not super instructive video to watch but quite funny to me :)
Also, It is very interesting that a little bit more then a year later, I would be moving to Brno to start a new phase of my life.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[GUADEC 2013 was hosted in Brno, Czech Republic and it was my first time doing a talk for a big audience, quite an experience! I can see how nervous I got in the two minutes I had for the interns lightning talk.
Not super instructive video to watch but quite funny to me :)
Also, It is very interesting that a little bit more then a year later, I would be moving to Brno to start a new phase of my life.
Video Slides
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
