<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Victor Toso</title>
        <link>https%3A//victortoso.com</link>
        <description>Nothing relevant</description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="https%3A//victortoso.com/tags/guadec/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Another GSoC on Grilo!</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/talks/talk-1401/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/talks/talk-1401/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;2014.guadec.org&quot;&gt;GUADEC 2014&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; took place in Strasbourg, France and that
was my first time in this beautiful country. My friend &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;yuumasato.wordpress.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Watson
Sato&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was also enrolled in the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developers.google.com&#x2F;open-source&#x2F;gsoc&#x2F;&quot;&gt;GSoC&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on GNOME and we were
able to travel and attend the conference together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time slot per intern for the light talk was very short once again but
everybody was able to summarize their work very well. Sadly the video was not
uploaded.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to come back to visit France more times in the future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;slides&#x2F;1401-guadec-light-talk-about-grilo.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Brno, GUADEC and Grilo</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1306/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/blog-1306/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Brno is amazing. Just amazing. The people from here try to be helpfull
even if they don&#x27;t speak a single word in English. The food is really
good and quite cheap and the city is beautiful! I&#x27;m glad that I still
have time for another tour around!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, travelling without many concerns, meeting amazing people and with
the opportunity to learn things you love... GUADEC has been an amazing
experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talks were really good but the people I have met here are awesome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m really glad to finally meet my mentor Juan Suárez and some folks
from Red Hat. It was awesome to talk with some others interns such as
Kalev, Marcos, Valentín, Alessandro, Bogdan and Carlos. It was brief but
really nice. Hope to meet everybody again next year!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here in GUADEC I had a lightning talk trying to briefly explain what my
GSoC is about. It was hard to do it in less then 3 minutes. I was quite
nervous too but everything went well :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anybody would like to know more about grilo or anything related ping
me on #grilo&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to talk with Juan about the GSoC project, Grilo
and some plans for the future. I&#x27;m a bit excited to keep contributing to
Grilo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank GNOME Fundation for the sponsorship and making
this travel possible; to Google for the Summer of Code Program; to
Fabiano Fidêncio for helping me A LOT in Brno.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#x27;s all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;1306-01-gnome-sponsored-badge.png&quot; alt=&quot;GNOME rocks!&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>My GSOC on Grilo!</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https%3A//victortoso.com/talks/talk-1301/</link>
                <guid>https%3A//victortoso.com/talks/talk-1301/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;2013.guadec.org&quot;&gt;GUADEC 2013&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was hosted in Brno, Czech Republic and it
was my first time doing a talk for a big audience, quite an experience! I can
see how nervous I got in the two minutes I had for the interns lightning talk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not super instructive video to watch but quite funny to me :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, It is very interesting that a little bit more then a year later, I would
be moving to Brno to start a new phase of my life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.superlectures.com&#x2F;guadec2013&#x2F;interns-lightning-talks?start=1:21:12&quot;&gt;Video&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;slides&#x2F;1301-guadec-light-talk-about-grilo.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
