<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <docs>https://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <title>Red Hat on Victor Toso</title>
    <link>http://victortoso.com/tags/red-hat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Red Hat on Victor Toso</description>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo 0.55.0-DEV</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 23:34:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
      <atom:link href="http://victortoso.com/tags/red-hat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>One year</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1501/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 23:34:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1501/</guid>
        <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost one year since my last blog post. One year since I got married and left Brazil to live in Czech Republic. In my last post I talked about all the changes I was passing through but no change is bigger than having a baby. Tereza has almost 4 months now :)
One year at Red Hat and Spice.
Even with the great amount of things to do in personal and professional life, I want to keep making GNOME better as much as I can in my free time and thus I want to get back to blogging again.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[It&amp;rsquo;s been almost one year since my last blog post. One year since I got married and left Brazil to live in Czech Republic. In my last post I talked about all the changes I was passing through but no change is bigger than having a baby. Tereza has almost 4 months now :)
One year at Red Hat and Spice.
Even with the great amount of things to do in personal and professional life, I want to keep making GNOME better as much as I can in my free time and thus I want to get back to blogging again.
I&amp;rsquo;ve finally managed to migrate from Blogger to Pelican so I hope that more personal posts like this one will not be part of Planet GNOME in the future :)
I also plan to blog more about personal stuff such as being a father or living abroad. I hope that it can ease the distance from family and friends in Brazil.
This one year was just crazy. Time flies and nothing like raising a child to realize that.
Cheers!
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello new life</title>
        <link>http://victortoso.com/blog/1408/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 21:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <guid>http://victortoso.com/blog/1408/</guid>
        <description>Since the end of the Google Summer of Code 2014 so many things have happened that It is really hard to make a simple blog post about it&amp;hellip; but I must try :)
New job Well, along with the GSoC I&amp;rsquo;ve applied to a job at Red Hat and the process ended in August. Since October 15th I am part of the Spice team and I will be working at the Brno office in Czech Republic.</description>
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Since the end of the Google Summer of Code 2014 so many things have happened that It is really hard to make a simple blog post about it&amp;hellip; but I must try :)
New job Well, along with the GSoC I&amp;rsquo;ve applied to a job at Red Hat and the process ended in August. Since October 15th I am part of the Spice team and I will be working at the Brno office in Czech Republic.
I am really excited with the work and with the team. I am learning a lot already.
New City I have visited Brno at GUADEC 2013, lovely city. I feel safe here unlike Campinas in Brazil.
I have great expectations about living here and so do my wife after reading Christian&amp;rsquo;s blog post about leaving Brno.
Married Yay ;) Yes, biggest decision of my life.
We have been together for almost three years now and we were living together for almost one year which made this decision straightforward for me. Catielle is a wonderful person and I am really happy with our marriage. I feel that we are going to be very happy here in Brno.
Pending Well, I was quite a busy in the last two months but I still have a lot of things to do!
A few blog posts about GUADEC, GSoC and Grilo I want to move this Blog to Pelican :-) Finishing off a few things related to the last GSoC project, making it upstream! Writing a documentation for the lua-factory plugin :-)
That&amp;rsquo;s all for now! I will be back hacking and blogging now that things are getting calmer.
]]></content:encoded>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
